<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technology on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/categories/technology/</link><description>Recent content in Technology on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 08:06:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Methodical versus Systematic</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/methodical-versus-systematic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/methodical-versus-systematic/</guid><description>I recently was assigned a CSS layout problem. As I was working on it I realized I hadn&amp;rsquo;t done CSS for a while. I also noticed I was thinking in a slightly different manner then when I&amp;rsquo;m writing PHP or JavaScript. I was thinking systematically about the problem, instead of thinking methodically.
The CSS layout system (I&amp;rsquo;m talking here about last-generation pre-grid CSS layout) centers around the Box Model. What this means is an element is comprised of the content, padding, border and margins, in that order from inside out.</description></item><item><title>Local Overrides in Chrome</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/chrome-local-overrides/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/chrome-local-overrides/</guid><description>At the beginning of this year Chrome came out with Local Overrides features for Chrome 65. This is related, but distinct from Workspaces, which is a way to save your devtools changes to a local project. While Workspaces seems neat, it&amp;rsquo;s rare that I&amp;rsquo;m working on a site whose code isn&amp;rsquo;t generated by some server-side tool. However, with Local Overrides I can work in the devtools inspector, and still persist those changes between page loads, even if they are separate from the project.</description></item><item><title>Easy Peasy React Cheesy</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/easy-peasy-react-cheesy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/easy-peasy-react-cheesy/</guid><description>Last week on twitter Dan Abramov was highlighting some of the easy ways to get your feet wet with React. I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with React for a while, and had heard the idea that one could add React as an individual component, or widget, to an already existing site. This looked like a good opportunity to try it out.
Caveat before we begin, the docs are great, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing I&amp;rsquo;m expanding here on what&amp;rsquo;s already covered in the docs.</description></item><item><title>Slide 'n Scroll fun</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/slide-n-scroll-fun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/slide-n-scroll-fun/</guid><description>I was tasked with creating a scroll animation, something that I’ve done before, but in a very ad-hoc fashion. I think the first time I did a “parallax” style scroll I did something like this:
That worked fine on an overpowered PC and when it was moving a tiny image up and off the page, but the next task was to move an image across the page in response to scrolling, and I wanted to make sure it was performant on all devices.</description></item><item><title>Arduino robot build</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/arduino-robot-build/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 13:52:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/arduino-robot-build/</guid><description>I’m a perennial tinkerer, and as such have always been fascinated by Arduino. When I first started using computers I wanted to trigger events in the real world, that wasn’t realized until I purchased an Arduino clone from Sparkfun.
After blinking the led I struggled to find a real-world use for the thing. After a short-lived foray into making a washing-machine monitor, it sat for a long time gathering dust.</description></item><item><title>This weird trick to hide your site name</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/alphabet-handles-logo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 01:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/alphabet-handles-logo/</guid><description>I took a look at Google’s parent company Alphabet’s website today. It a clean little one-pager. The thing I noticed was their handling of the logo.
At first it looks like a simple logo font. Turns out their doing some old-school web shenanigans.
`#logo{</description></item><item><title>SVG&amp;#8217;s on a local environment</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/svgs-on-a-local-environment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 12:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/svgs-on-a-local-environment/</guid><description>This afternoon I was replacing a .png image with an .svg. Working in my local development environment, I started with a simple ``. It looked like a broken link. Next I went to CSS-Tricks and used the first fall-back technique he lists:
``
This also resulted in a broken link.
I banged my head against the wall for at least an hour, checking the path, swapping .svg for .png. Everything I could think of.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Mess</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/facebook-mess/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 14:52:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/facebook-mess/</guid><description>This year I noticed that my Facebook had become high-jacked by viral-videos, Upworthy-style misleading article titles and pictures of very small houses. I have a few specific functions I want Facebook to perform for me in this order.
Keep up to date with the major and minor life changes of a broad group of associates I wouldn’t otherwise keep in touch with. I think of loose friends from college, high school friends, family friends, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>