<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/</link><description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrate to Hugo</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/post/2021-12-27-migrate-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/post/2021-12-27-migrate-to-hugo/</guid><description>This is a series of posts inspired by my own reaction to a tweet about not blogging. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll migrate my blog to Hugo, which is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to try for a while.
Step One; Install Hugo brew install hugo hugo version Okay, easy peasey.
Step Two; Migrate! There are a few tools to migrate, but there&amp;rsquo;s a built-in CLI that looks super easy:
Import your site from other web site generators like Jekyll.</description></item><item><title>Switching to Linux</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/post/2021-09-01-linux-v-mac/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/post/2021-09-01-linux-v-mac/</guid><description>A tale of failure I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a number of blog posts where developers complain about the Apple ecosystem and show how they made the switch from MacOS to Linux. Usually, they have a complaint about the company, their anti-competitive behavior, or their intrusiveness, or their non-web focus, or their relentless un-openness. I usually find myself nodding along, and I&amp;rsquo;m usually inspired by their post to try out some combination of alternative services or hand-rolled versions of the key Apple applications.</description></item><item><title>Advent of Swift</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/post/2020-12-9-advent-of-swift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/post/2020-12-9-advent-of-swift/</guid><description>Like so many of my potential readers I’m participating in this year’s advent of code. This presents me with an opportunity to learn Swift, Apple’s app-oriented language and successor to Objective-C. There are always challenges learning a new language, and I expected those, what surprised me was how far Swift is from my daily drivers: JavaScript and PHP, and my go to “toy” language, Python. (Toy, as in, I almost never finish a Python project, not that the language is a toy).</description></item><item><title>Remove React</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/npm-remove-react/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/npm-remove-react/</guid><description>In the face of police violence toward Black Americans I feel mostly helpless and useless. I&amp;rsquo;m not in the path of police violence; I&amp;rsquo;m white, employed, and comfortable, and with two kids depending on my income, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to remain inactive and on the sidelines. While I can state clearly, Black Lives Matter, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have an obvious means of action.
But I want to examine a little deeper how I&amp;rsquo;m complicit in a system of white supremacy through my engagement with the React framework.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Closures</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/exploring-closures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 20:34:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/exploring-closures/</guid><description>I was inspired by Eric Elliot&amp;rsquo;s post on closures. He posted on twitter with this super simple example const secret = msg =&amp;gt; () =&amp;gt; msg;. Here&amp;rsquo;s the article, as usual I&amp;rsquo;ll encourage you to read that first: https://medium.com/javascript-scene/master-the-javascript-interview-what-is-a-closure-b2f0d2152b36
The long and short is that the automatic lexical closure in javascript allows us to give us data privacy, this can be compared to protected or private properties in OOP.
Note: In the following example I&amp;rsquo;m missing the main point!</description></item><item><title>Finding the best job</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/best-job-ever/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 20:34:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/best-job-ever/</guid><description>I like my job, but it&amp;rsquo;s not the best job. And since I deserver the best job it&amp;rsquo;s time I found it, lucky for me Outside Magazine already did the work and found the best 100 places to work!
But Clayton, you say, that&amp;rsquo;s a two year old post, and how come you trust some magazine to decide what is best for you? Well, I don&amp;rsquo;t, and it is, but I&amp;rsquo;m taking the day off and web scrapping relaxes me.</description></item><item><title>Methodical versus Systematic</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/methodical-versus-systematic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/methodical-versus-systematic/</guid><description>I recently was assigned a CSS layout problem. As I was working on it I realized I hadn&amp;rsquo;t done CSS for a while. I also noticed I was thinking in a slightly different manner then when I&amp;rsquo;m writing PHP or JavaScript. I was thinking systematically about the problem, instead of thinking methodically.
The CSS layout system (I&amp;rsquo;m talking here about last-generation pre-grid CSS layout) centers around the Box Model. What this means is an element is comprised of the content, padding, border and margins, in that order from inside out.</description></item><item><title>Local Overrides in Chrome</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/chrome-local-overrides/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/chrome-local-overrides/</guid><description>At the beginning of this year Chrome came out with Local Overrides features for Chrome 65. This is related, but distinct from Workspaces, which is a way to save your devtools changes to a local project. While Workspaces seems neat, it&amp;rsquo;s rare that I&amp;rsquo;m working on a site whose code isn&amp;rsquo;t generated by some server-side tool. However, with Local Overrides I can work in the devtools inspector, and still persist those changes between page loads, even if they are separate from the project.</description></item><item><title>Easy Peasy React Cheesy</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/easy-peasy-react-cheesy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/easy-peasy-react-cheesy/</guid><description>Last week on twitter Dan Abramov was highlighting some of the easy ways to get your feet wet with React. I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with React for a while, and had heard the idea that one could add React as an individual component, or widget, to an already existing site. This looked like a good opportunity to try it out.
Caveat before we begin, the docs are great, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing I&amp;rsquo;m expanding here on what&amp;rsquo;s already covered in the docs.</description></item><item><title>Slide 'n Scroll fun</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/slide-n-scroll-fun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/slide-n-scroll-fun/</guid><description>I was tasked with creating a scroll animation, something that I’ve done before, but in a very ad-hoc fashion. I think the first time I did a “parallax” style scroll I did something like this:
That worked fine on an overpowered PC and when it was moving a tiny image up and off the page, but the next task was to move an image across the page in response to scrolling, and I wanted to make sure it was performant on all devices.</description></item><item><title>Arduino robot build</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/arduino-robot-build/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 13:52:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/arduino-robot-build/</guid><description>I’m a perennial tinkerer, and as such have always been fascinated by Arduino. When I first started using computers I wanted to trigger events in the real world, that wasn’t realized until I purchased an Arduino clone from Sparkfun.
After blinking the led I struggled to find a real-world use for the thing. After a short-lived foray into making a washing-machine monitor, it sat for a long time gathering dust.</description></item><item><title>Preventing and allowing linebreaks</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/preventing-and-allowing-linebreaks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 13:14:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/preventing-and-allowing-linebreaks/</guid><description>This is a trick I figured out when a client wanted to have chevron icon to the right of a block title. However, they didn’t want the chevron to break to it’s own line, unless the title itself broke to the new line. Basically, the chevron need to act like it was part of the last word, and maintain space between itself and that word. Also, the chervon moves to the right on hover.</description></item><item><title>This weird trick to hide your site name</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/alphabet-handles-logo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 01:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/alphabet-handles-logo/</guid><description>I took a look at Google’s parent company Alphabet’s website today. It a clean little one-pager. The thing I noticed was their handling of the logo.
At first it looks like a simple logo font. Turns out their doing some old-school web shenanigans.
`#logo{</description></item><item><title>SVG&amp;#8217;s on a local environment</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/svgs-on-a-local-environment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 12:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/svgs-on-a-local-environment/</guid><description>This afternoon I was replacing a .png image with an .svg. Working in my local development environment, I started with a simple ``. It looked like a broken link. Next I went to CSS-Tricks and used the first fall-back technique he lists:
``
This also resulted in a broken link.
I banged my head against the wall for at least an hour, checking the path, swapping .svg for .png. Everything I could think of.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Mess</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/facebook-mess/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 14:52:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/facebook-mess/</guid><description>This year I noticed that my Facebook had become high-jacked by viral-videos, Upworthy-style misleading article titles and pictures of very small houses. I have a few specific functions I want Facebook to perform for me in this order.
Keep up to date with the major and minor life changes of a broad group of associates I wouldn’t otherwise keep in touch with. I think of loose friends from college, high school friends, family friends, etc.</description></item><item><title>Keyboard Shortcuts</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/keyboard-shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 15:22:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/keyboard-shortcuts/</guid><description>I spent a solid hour this morning perfecting my keyboard shortcuts. Productivity, at this point, is really more of a feeling than something to measure. I’m sure if I actually measured the amount of time saved by Command + Tab versus using the mouse I would only be saving a few seconds every day. The point of streamlining my computer processes is not the time saved, but the feeling of streamlining.</description></item><item><title>Eclecticism</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/eclecticism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 17:22:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/eclecticism/</guid><description>I have a number of subjects that I’ve been ruminating but haven’t sat down to explore further: custom WordPress themes, our home entertainment set-up, merging all contacts, learning ukulele with a 2 year old, etc. Instead I think I’ll just take a minute to look at how I spend a day.
It’s now 12:03 on a Wednesday. It has been a slow work week. I finished a project last Friday. I’m waiting on feedback on two other projects.</description></item><item><title>new website using twitter bootstrap</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/new-website-using-twitter-bootstrap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 13:06:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/new-website-using-twitter-bootstrap/</guid><description>I recently did a quick redesign of my work website artbuildcreative.com. I whipped up this design flat in photoshop. Those grey rectangles are thumbnail links to projects.I’ve also been working with the twitter bootstrap framework. It’s simple a set of CSS and Javascript libraries that make laying out and building responsive websites very easy. It includes a whole slew of pre-built classes to do this from formatting: “.col-md-6” to assets “.</description></item><item><title>how not to learn SASS</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/how-not-to-learn-sass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 20:34:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/hugo-blog/how-not-to-learn-sass/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>