<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Uncategorized on Sweating the Small Stuff</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/categories/uncategorized/</link><description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Sweating the Small Stuff</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/claytron5000">Clayton Salem&lt;/a> 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://claytron5000.github.io/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remove React</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/npm-remove-react/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/npm-remove-react/</guid><description>In the face of police violence toward Black Americans I feel mostly helpless and useless. I&amp;rsquo;m not in the path of police violence; I&amp;rsquo;m white, employed, and comfortable, and with two kids depending on my income, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to remain inactive and on the sidelines. While I can state clearly, Black Lives Matter, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have an obvious means of action.
But I want to examine a little deeper how I&amp;rsquo;m complicit in a system of white supremacy through my engagement with the React framework.</description></item><item><title>Preventing and allowing linebreaks</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/preventing-and-allowing-linebreaks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 13:14:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/preventing-and-allowing-linebreaks/</guid><description>This is a trick I figured out when a client wanted to have chevron icon to the right of a block title. However, they didn’t want the chevron to break to it’s own line, unless the title itself broke to the new line. Basically, the chevron need to act like it was part of the last word, and maintain space between itself and that word. Also, the chervon moves to the right on hover.</description></item><item><title>Keyboard Shortcuts</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/keyboard-shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 15:22:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/keyboard-shortcuts/</guid><description>I spent a solid hour this morning perfecting my keyboard shortcuts. Productivity, at this point, is really more of a feeling than something to measure. I’m sure if I actually measured the amount of time saved by Command + Tab versus using the mouse I would only be saving a few seconds every day. The point of streamlining my computer processes is not the time saved, but the feeling of streamlining.</description></item><item><title>Eclecticism</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/eclecticism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 17:22:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/eclecticism/</guid><description>I have a number of subjects that I’ve been ruminating but haven’t sat down to explore further: custom WordPress themes, our home entertainment set-up, merging all contacts, learning ukulele with a 2 year old, etc. Instead I think I’ll just take a minute to look at how I spend a day.
It’s now 12:03 on a Wednesday. It has been a slow work week. I finished a project last Friday. I’m waiting on feedback on two other projects.</description></item><item><title>new website using twitter bootstrap</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/new-website-using-twitter-bootstrap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 13:06:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/new-website-using-twitter-bootstrap/</guid><description>I recently did a quick redesign of my work website artbuildcreative.com. I whipped up this design flat in photoshop. Those grey rectangles are thumbnail links to projects.I’ve also been working with the twitter bootstrap framework. It’s simple a set of CSS and Javascript libraries that make laying out and building responsive websites very easy. It includes a whole slew of pre-built classes to do this from formatting: “.col-md-6” to assets “.</description></item><item><title>how not to learn SASS</title><link>https://claytron5000.github.io/how-not-to-learn-sass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 20:34:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://claytron5000.github.io/how-not-to-learn-sass/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>